

JENNIFER CAMPBELL: CV

I am an experienced charity copywriter, journalist, editor, proofreader and project manager. I have worked with more than 40 charities in the UK and worldwide to create copy and publications that engage, inspire – and make readers take action.

I can manage editorial projects from concepts right through to print, delivering publications on brand, on time and on budget.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Charity Writer/Editor and Project Manager. April 2011 – present

I write, edit, proofread and project manage the production of publications for charities including WWF, the British Lung Foundation, ActionAid, Climate Action Network Europe, the British Ecological Society and Changing Faces.

ngo.media Writer/Editor. July 2008 – April 2011

ngo.media is the UK's leading copywriting, publications and training agency working only with charities and other socially-driven organisations.

My work there for clients such as Drinkaware, BTCV, Dyslexia Scotland, the Energy Saving Trust, Macmillan Cancer Support, School Home Support, Help the Aged and Bowel Cancer UK included:

- Taking overall responsibility for editorial projects, from agreeing a brief to print.
- Writing brochures, leaflets, annual reviews, news, features, newsletters, e-newsletters, web content, reports and more.
- Editing (often complex) text written by experts into plain English, readable copy.
- Proofreading, taking responsibility for spotting errors in publications before print.
- Managing design and print.
- Commissioning work from freelance writers and other team members.
- Presenting seminars on good writing for charities at charity communications events.



Freelance journalist 2005 – 2008

News and features published in The Big Issue, Daily Express, The Sunday Times, The Sunday Herald Magazine, Daily Mail, The Observer and The Perthshire Advertiser.

EDUCATION

2007 - 08 **City University** – postgraduate diploma in magazine journalism, with merit. Interviewer of the Year nominee at *Press Gazette* Student Journalism Awards 2008.

2002 - 07 **University of St Andrews** – MA (Honours) 2:1 Spanish and International Relations (with integrated year abroad, spent as an English teacher in Spain)

OTHER SKILLS

Teeline shorthand at 100 words per minute

Languages: fluent Spanish, good French (I studied French for two years at university)